Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Lois Gaeta Papers, 1956-1961 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Lois Gaeta papers 1956-1961 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company.
0.4 Linear Feet 100 Items
Lois Gaeta was a television and radio script writer at the J. Walter Thompson (JWT) advertising agency from 1955 to 1961.
The Lois Gaeta Papers span the years 1956 to 1961 and include television and radio scripts, filmed commercial spots, as well as print advertisements and packaging samples, that document Gaeta's work as a script and copy writer for JWT. Companies represented include Beecham Products (Eno), Blue Cross/Blue Shield, Colgate-Palmolive (Stripe toothpaste), Eastman Kodak, Mentholatum, Reader's Digest, and W.F. Young (Absorbine Jr.).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, audiovisual originals are closed to researchers. Use copies are available int the collection.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Lois Gaeta Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2002 and 2004.
Biographical Note
After graduating from Mount Holyoke College, Lois Gaeta worked at the J. Walter Thompson Company advertising agency as a script writer for television and radio commercials during the years 1955 through 1961. Later in her career, Gaeta worked in video and in continuing education programs in the medical profession.
Collection Overview
The Lois Gaeta Papers span the years 1956 to 1961 and include television and radio scripts, filmed commercial spots, as well as print advertisements and packaging samples, that document Gaeta's work as a script and copy writer for JWT. Companies represented include Beecham Products (Eno), Blue Cross/Blue Shield, Colgate-Palmolive (Stripe toothpaste), Eastman Kodak, Mentholatum, Reader's Digest, and W.F. Young (Absorbine Jr.).
The collection is arranged into three series: General Files; Company Files; and Audiovisual Materials. The General Files Series includes clippings, correspondence and other printed materials, arranged alphabetically. The Company Files Series consists of radio and television scripts, print advertisements and packaging examples, arranged alphabetically by company name. Therein, scripts are arranged chronologically by year. The Audiovisual Materials Series consists of 16mm black-and-white films of television commercials, primarily for Mentholatum.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Gaeta, Lois
J. Walter Thompson Company
Beecham Pharmaceuticals U.K.
Blue Cross and Blue Shield Association
Colgate-Palmolive Company
Eastman Kodak Company
Mentholatum Company Inc
Reader's Digest Association
W.F. Young, Inc. [not LC]
Advertising -- Motion pictures
Advertising -- United States -- History -- 20th century
Radio advertising
Radio scripts
Television advertising
Television scripts
Women in the advertising industry
Black-and-white films.
Packaging.
Proofs (printed matter)
16mm.
Motion pictures.
Scripts (documents)
Tear sheets.
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following collections within the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives: Review Board Records; Account Files Collection; Wallace W. Elton Papers; John F. Devine Papers; Granger Tripp Papers; Shirley F. Woodall Papers; Dan Seymour Papers; and the Rena Bartos Papers. In addition, materials relating to Kodak may be found in the Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements; and the Wayne P. Ellis Collection of Kodakiana. Materials relating to Colgate-Palmolive may be found in the D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives; and the Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records. Materials relating to radio advertising may also be found in the Walter Weir Papers.
Contents of Collection
- General Files Series, 1957-1961 and undated, (1 Box)
  Includes clippings, correspondence and other printed materials. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1959
  - Printed materials, 1960-1961
- Company Files Series, 1956-1961 and undated, (1 Box)
  Includes radio and television scripts, print advertisements and packaging examples. Arranged alphabetically by company name, and scripts are arranged chronologically by year therein.
  - Beecham Products (Eno), 1960 and undated (Box 1)
    - Package inserts, undated
    - Scripts, 1960
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield scripts, 1961
  - Colgate-Palmolive (Stripe toothpaste) advertisement, 1960
  - Crane scripts, undated
  - Eastman Kodak scripts, 1958
  - Fleischmann's Yeast (Standard Brands) scripts, 1956
  - Foundation for Commercial Banks scripts, undated
  - Macmillan scripts, undated
  - Mentholatum
    - Print advertisements and packaging examples, 1957-1961
    - Scripts, 1956-1960, (4 folders)
  - Peru International scripts, 1958
  - Radio Free Europe scripts, 1956
  - Reader's Digest scripts, 1960-1961
  - Scott Paper Co. scripts, undated
  - Sylvania scripts, 1956-1957
  - W.F. Young (Absorbine Jr.)
    - Print advertisements, 1960-1961
    - Scripts, 1958-1961
- Audiovisual Materials, 1958-1960 and undated, (2 Boxes)
  Consists of television spot advertisements for Mentholatum products.
  Restrictions on access: Originals are closed to researchers. Use copies are available in the collection.
  - Originals (Closed to researchers)
    - OR1. Five Mentholatum spots (includes Deep Heat Rub and Colban). Format: 16mm. Undated. TRT: 5:00 (Box 2)
    - OR2. Mentholatum Child spot. Format: 16mm. Date: 1958. TRT: 1:00
    - OR3. Mentholatum Rain spot. Format: 16mm. Date: 1960. TRT: 1:00
    - OR4. Mentholatum Colban spot. Format: 16mm. Date: 1959. TRT: 1:00
    - OR5. Mentholatum Xcursion spot. Format: 16mm. Undated. TRT: 1:00
  - Production Masters (Not for research use)
    - MC1. Master for OR1-OR5. Format: Betacam SP. Created: 2008 (Box 3)
  - Use Copies
    - UC1. Use copy for OR1-OR5. Format: DVD. Created: 2008 (Box 1)